ARGHYA CHATTERJEE

60, BC Das Lane, Lalbagh, Dhaka, BD +88-01943753798

arghyame20buet@gmail.com

https://arghyachatterjee.github.io

A machine learning researcher experienced in applying Deep Learning, Edge & Cloud Computing for Computer Vision (CV) related practical applications, Advanced Perception (CV & LIDAR) based SLAM for semantic awareness of the environment and multi-agent collaboration for autonomous robotic exploration to encourage collaborative endeavor in perceptually degraded environments & explore outer space for better future of mankind.

EDUCATION

Bangladesh University of Engineering and Technology, Dhaka, Bangladesh

Degree: BSc. in Mechanical Engineering Feb 2015 - Sept 2019

CGPA: 3.14/4.00

Khulna Public College, Khulna, Bangladesh

Degree: HSC in Science Jul 2012 - Aug 2014 GPA: 5.00/5.00 Class Position: $1^{st}/60$

Khulna Bidyut Kendra Secondary School, Khulna, Bangladesh

Degree: SSC in Science Jan 2010 - May 2012

GPA: 5.00/5.00 Class Position: 1st/60

RESEARCH & PROJECT EXPERIENCE

Team Member, Team CoSTAR

DARPA organized SubT Challenge for Team CoSTAR of NASA JPL Jul 2020 – Present Perception Team Leader: Dr. Benjamin Morrell (NASA JPL) California, USA Topic: Advanced perception based multi-robot SLAM algorithms efficiency, accuracy & robustness testing along with object detection & localization capability analysis for robots like Spot, Husky & Roller-copter with special autonomy setup (built by Team CoSTAR) mounted.

Project Supervisor & Educator, Teams from Bangladesh

JAXA (& NASA) Kibo-Astrobee ISS Robot Programming Challenge Jan 2020 – Present International Project Coordinator: Mizanul H. Chowdhury (MIT) Tokyo, Japan Topic: Autonomously operate Astrobee (A free flying robot) inside ISS avoiding obstacles with 3D perception, following way points and detecting QR & AR Tag.

Graduate Research Assistant at Mars Rover Lab, BUET

Software Team Advisor (& Ex. Lead) of Interplanetar for URC & ERC

Sep 2019 – Present

Supervisor: Dr. Md. Ashiqur Rahman (BUET)

Topic: Autonomous Navigation Based on GPS, SLAM, AR Tag and Object Detection for Safe

Exploration of Rovers on Rough Terrains, Caves and Mineral Ores of Earth and Mars.

• Researcher & Collaborator

Undergraduate Thesis

Supervisors: Dr. Maglub Al Nur (BUET) and Dr. Muhammad Abir (MIT)

Dhaka, Bangladesh
Topic: Computational Investigation on Pool Boiling IR Images for Segmentation of Dry Spots
Automatically and Evaluating Performance of Traditional Image Processing and Deep Neural
Networks in Quantifying Dry Area Segments.

• Researcher & Team Leader

Undergraduate Project
Supervisors: Dr. M.A. Rashid Sarkar and Musanna Galib (BUET)

Topic: Fire and Flood Fighter Octocopter (UAV) for Extinguishing Fire in Fire Affected Buildings and Areas, and Distributing Flood Reliefs to people in Flood Affected Zones.

• Researcher & Technical Lead

Microsoft BD Internship Project

Feb 2017 - May 2017

Supervisors: Sonia B. Kabir and Ashikur Rahman (Microsoft)

Topic: Earlier Screening of Particular Disability in Children Through Mobile Application Using Microsoft Products like Azure Cloud Platform and Bing Maps Server.

• Researcher & Team Leader

Undergraduate Project

Supervisors: Dr. M.A. Rashid Sarkar and Dr. A. B. M. Alim Al Islam (BUET)

Dhaka, Bangladesh
Topic: Hand Wearable Solar Powered Obstacle Detection and Safe Navigation Device for Blind
People in Low Cost.

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

•	JAXA Kibo-Astrobee ISS Robot Programming Challenge	Jan 2020 - Present
	Instructor for Teams from BUET	Dhaka, Bangladesh
•	BUET Mars Rover Robotics Team	Sep 2019 - Present
	Instructor at Model & Project Lab (Mars Rover Lab), BUET	Dhaka, Bangladesh
•	National Space Carnival & Camp	Sep 2019 - Present
	Instructor & Academic Coordinator for Workshops & Camps	Dhaka, Bangladesh
•	Bangladesh Astronomical Society	Jan 2017 – May 2019
	Instructor for Workshops & Seminars	Dhaka, Bangladesh

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Bangladesh Astronomy Research Center (BARC)
 Advisor & Member
 Activities: Give advice on research activities & how the organization should operate.

Youthprenuer Network (A Social Welfare Organization)
 Head of STEM Education & Development
 Activities: Instructed, Organized and Lead Projects, Workshops, Olympiads and Camps in Educational Institutions to Promote STEM Education in Bangladesh.

American Astronomical Society

Country Coordinator & Member

Activities: Celebrated International Astronomical Events in Bangladesh in accordance with AAS, and Reported to Proper Authority for Publishing on their Monthly Magazines.

PUBLICATIONS

- Matteo Palieri, Benjamin Morrell, Abhishek Thakur, Arghya Chatterjee, Kamak Ebadi, Jeremy Nash, Christoforos Kanellakis, Luca Carlone, Cataldo Guaragnella, Ali-akbar Agha-mohammadi, "LOCUS: A Multi-Sensor Lidar-Centric Solution for High-Precision Odometry and 3D Mapping in Real-Time," Journal of IEEE Robotics and Automation Letters (Accepted).
- A. Chatterjee, M. Galib and M. A. R. Sarkar, "Application of Arduino in designing modern electromechanical laboratory," 2017 IEEE International Conference on Power, Control, Signals and Instrumentation Engineering (ICPCSI), Chennai, 2017, pp. 222-225.
- A. Chatterjee, S. Dutta, P. Sarkar and A. B. M. A. A. Islam, "Obstacle Detector for Blind People with Low Cost (Poster Presentation)," *Proceedings of* 2017 International Conference on Networking, Systems and Security (NSysS), Dhaka, 2017.

INTERNSHIPS & TRAININGS

•	Microsoft Bangladesh	Feb 2017 - May 2017
	Internship Project: Disabling Disability through Microsoft Products	Dhaka, Bangladesh
•	Khulna Power Company Limited	Oct 2018 - Oct 2018
	Training: Power Plant Visit & Industrial Attachment (3 weeks)	Khulna, Bangladesh

SKILL SETS

- Prg. Language: Python, C++, C#, C, R, Arduino, Java, Java S, HTML, PHP, CSS, & LATEX.
- Framework & OS: ROS, OpenCV, PCL, Nvidia Isaac SDK, Keras, TensorFlow, PyTorch, Caffe, CUDA, OpenGL, Kubernetes, .NET, Django, Linux, Mac, Windows & Android.
- Software & Tool: Git & GitHub, Docker, MIPAR, Solidworks, Ansys, PLC, Blender, Unity & UE 4, Verge3D, Carla Simulator, Microsoft Airsim, OpenPose3D, Meshroom, Meshlab, CloudCompare, OpenDroneMap, OpenSpace, Photoshop, Kdenlive & MS Office Family.
- IDE, Compiler & Text Editor: CodeBlocks, Microsoft Visual Studio, MATLAB, Atom, Jupiter Notebook, PyCharm, Android Studio, Nodejs, IntelliJ IDEA, VS Code & Notepad++.
- Cloud Platform: AWS Compute, AWS RoboMaker & Storage, GCP, Google Colab.
- Hardware: GPS (RTK), IMU, VLP-16 (3D) & RPLidar (2D) LIDAR, Intel Realsense D435i RGBD & L515 Lidar Camera, ZED 3D Camera, Nvidia Jetson & Intel NUC Boards, Arduino & Raspberry PI Boards, PX4, Ardupilot, VESC, BLDC motor, Nvidia AMD GTX Boards & Oculus Rift S VR Headset.
- Technology: Computer Vision, Image Proc., ML, DL, DRL, Object Detection & Recognition, Image Segmentation, Pose Tracking, SLAM, Photogrammetry, 3D Printing, AR, VR & MR, Game Dev, Web Dev, Video Editing, GPU, Edge & Cloud Computing.
- Language: Bangla, English & Hindi.
- Others: Astronomy, Creative Arts, Singing, Harmonium & Guitar Playing, Organizing, Show Hosting, Volunteering, Swimming, Cycling, Playing Cricket, Football & Badminton.

AWARDS, HONORS & SCHOLARSHIPS

Gold Medalist from Duke of Edinburgh International Foundation	Dec 2019
Awarded for Outstanding Extra-curricular & Service to the Society	London, UK
• 2 nd in Asia & 16 th Internationally in European Mars Rover Challenge	Sep 2019
European Space Foundation (ESF) & European Space Agency (ESA)	Kielce, PL
• Finalist in IEEE SS12 International Project Competition & Maker Fair	Jul 2017
SS12: Age of Innovation and Maker Fair 2017	Hyderabad, IN
• 1 st in National Project Show Competition (Senior Category)	May 2017
EEE Day, BUET	Dhaka, BD
 3rd in Inter University Project Show Competition 	Apr 2017
Mechanical Festival, BUET	Dhaka, BD
• 1 st in National Poster Presentation Competition	Mar 2017
Robolution, MIST	Dhaka, BD
 2nd in Inter University Project Show Competition 	Nov 2016
CSE Day, BUET	Dhaka, BD
• 1st in All Classes in Primary, Junior, Secondary & H. Secondary	2002-2014
Elizabeth Primary Sc., Khulna BKS Sc., Khulna Pub. Cl.	Khulna, BD
Govt. Board Scholarship in Primary, Junior, Secondary & H. Secondary	2006-2014
Education Board of Bangladesh Govt., Jessore	Khulna, BD
Olympiad Achievements:	
• 1 st in Reg. R. of Science Olympiad'14 • 1 st in Reg. R. of Zo	ology Olympiad'14

• 3rd in Reg. R. of Math Olympiad'14

CERTIFICATIONS

• Machine Learning by Stanford University on Coursera, Feb 2018.

• 3rd in Reg. & 10th in Nat. R. of Astro-Olympiad'13

- **Deep Learning Specialization** (5 course) by Deeplearning.ai on Coursera, Sept 2018.
- **Control of Mobile Robots** by Georgia Institute of Technology on Coursera. May 2020.
- Image & Video Processing by Duke University on Coursera, Nov 2018.
- Intro to Satellite Communications by Institut Mines Télécom on Coursera, May 2019.

- Wireless Communications for Everybody by Yonsei University on Coursera, Dec 2018.
- **AstroTech** by University of Edinburgh on Coursera, Dec 2019.
- A Course on **Nuclear Power Eng**. by Institute of Nuclear Power Engineering, BUET, Apr 2018.

LEADERSHIPS

• **Head** of STEM Education & Development

Software Team Lead

• **Technical Lead** of Internship Project

• **President** (Senior Rover Mate)

President

• Team Lead for Development & Planning

Youthprenuer Network
Team Interplanetar, BUET
Microsoft BD
BUET Rover Scout Group
Satyen Bose Science Club, BUET

ESAB, BUET Unit

VOLUNTEERING

• Sceptre (Poverty Alleviation Organization)

Activities: Org. free medical camps & distribute dress & sewing machines to poor people.

BUET Rover Scout Group

Activities: Volunteered on alumni day at BUET & org. flood relief distribution camp.

• Khulna Bidyut Kendra Secondary School Scout Group
Activities: Volunteered on medical camps, tree plantation events & sports day at KBKSS.

SEMINARS & WORKSHOPS

- International Youth Leadership Summit-2016 org. by BYLC.
- 4th BIRDS International Workshop on **Demystifying Satellites** org. by BRAC University.
- Seminar on **Zero Robotics** by M.H. Chowdhury of MIT org. by Dept. of Mech. Eng., BUET.
- Seminar on **Space Stories and ISS Experiences** by Astronaut Dr. Tess Caswell of NASA org. by Dept. of Civil Eng., BUET.
- Seminar on **4-fold Resolution Increase in Endoscopic Imaging** by J.M. Kahn of Stanford University, org. by Dept. of Biomedical Eng., BUET.
- Workshop on **ML, PCB, Graphic Designing, & Technical Paper Writing** org. by IEEE BDS.
- Workshop on CFD, Ansys Fluent, Solidworks & 3D Printing org. by Involute Tech BD.

MEMBERSHIPS

- Institute of Electrical and Electronics Eng. (IEEE)
- American Nuclear Society (ANS)
- Bangladesh Astronomy Research Center (BARC)
- American Astronomical Society (AAS)
- IEEE Robotics and Automation Society
- BYLC Graduate Network (BGN)

REFERENCES

Dr. Benjamin Morrell

Perception Team Leader, Team CoSTAR Ex. Post Doc Researcher, Caltech Robotics Technologist, NASA JPL. Email: benjamin.morrell@jpl.nasa.gov

Dr. Md. Ashiqur Rahman

Project Supervisor Professor, Dept. of Mech. Eng., BUET. Email: ashiqurrahman@me.buet.ac.bd Dr. Muhammad Abir

Thesis Co-Supervisor Ex. Post Doc. R. Associate, Dept. of NSE, MIT. Imaging Specialist, Phoenix Nuclear Labs. Email: miabir@mit.edu

• Mizanul H. Chowdhury

Project Supervisor Arch. & Admin of ZR, Space Systems Lab, MIT. Email: mizanul@mit.edu